<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/week4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my mom&amp;rsquo;s birthday last week! 🎉 🎉 🎉
But I didn&amp;rsquo;t forget about studying either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the discipline &amp;ldquo;Mathematical foundations of information protection and information security&amp;rdquo;, I completed the fifth laboratory work, in which it was necessary to implement probabilistic algorithms for checking the simplicity of a number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also completed the fifth laboratory work in the discipline &amp;ldquo;Scientific Programming&amp;rdquo;, thanks to which I learned even more about Octave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote the third test paper on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Additional chapters of queuing theory&amp;rdquo;. Wow, there are so many tests on this subject!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continue to keep you informed of my academic achievements. Au revoir! 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/lang_sci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/lang_sci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A scientific programming language&lt;/strong&gt; is one that is designed and optimized for the use of mathematical formula and matrices.[2] Such languages are characterized not only by the availability of libraries performing mathematical or scientific functions, but by the syntax of the language itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples-of-scientific-programming-languages&#34;&gt;Examples of scientific programming languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ALGOT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fortran&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MATLAB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;each-language-has-its-own-peculiarities-and-only-you-decide-which-one-to-use&#34;&gt;Each language has its own peculiarities, and only you decide which one to use.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my birthday last week! 🎉 🎉 🎉
But I didn&amp;rsquo;t forget about studying either. I managed to complete several academic tasks, which I would like to tell you more about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the discipline &amp;ldquo;Mathematical foundations of information protection and information security&amp;rdquo;, I completed the fourth laboratory work, in which it was necessary to implement four algorithms for finding the greatest common divisor. I remembered the school 👶&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She also completed the fourth laboratory work on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Scientific Programming&amp;rdquo;, which was aimed at solving systems of linear equations using Octave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote the second test paper on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Additional chapters of the theory of queuing&amp;rdquo;. Waiting for the results 🤞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continue to keep you informed of my academic achievements. Au revoir! 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a report</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making a report&lt;/strong&gt; is a time-consuming but necessary process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithm-for-creating-a-report-in-markdown&#34;&gt;Algorithm for creating a report in Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the report template. The template will greatly simplify the process of creating a report and selecting the best parameters. In the future, you can use your own reports as a template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a program to work with Markdown files. I use Atom and I can recommend it to you: a user-friendly interface, the ability to download additional packages (for example, to preview files) and a large selection of themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare images for the report and always keep the Markdown syntax tab open at hand. You can always forget something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start creating!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert the report to the desired format and admire your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-good-that-there-is-markdown&#34;&gt;How good that there is Markdown.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight markup languages</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/lang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/lang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightweight Markup Language&lt;/strong&gt; is a markup language with a simple, unobtrusive syntax. In fact, the syntax is so simple that anyone can quickly learn how to use these markup languages. The key advantage of this type of language is that it is designed in such a way that it is easy to enter annotated text in a text editor and at the same time easy to read in raw form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-and-benefits&#34;&gt;Application and Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of uses for lightweight markup languages. Lightweight markup languages are useful when writing texts, as they allow you to save a lot of time on creating HTML tags manually, speeding up any process related to writing. They are also particularly effective where the reader wants to read the source document as well as the output data. Moreover, lightweight markup languages are often used in web publications, including wikis and blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asciidoc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;each-language-has-its-own-peculiarities-and-only-you-decide-which-one-to-use&#34;&gt;Each language has its own peculiarities, and only you decide which one to use.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/week2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I managed to complete several academic tasks, which I would like to tell you more about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the discipline &amp;ldquo;Mathematical foundations of information security and information security&amp;rdquo;, I completed the third laboratory work, the topic of which was encryption by gamming. Implemented encryption using a finite- length gamma 👏🏼&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She also completed the third laboratory work in the discipline &amp;ldquo;Scientific Programming&amp;rdquo;, which was aimed at gaining skills in working with Octave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed laboratory work on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Modeling of wireless networks&amp;rdquo;, thanks to which she learned how to apply distributions to transform random variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She wrote a test paper on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Additional chapters of queuing theory&amp;rdquo;, in which a mathematical model of a network with unicast connections was considered. To be honest, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t difficult. But in a week there will be another test in this discipline. Wish me luck!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continue to keep you informed of my academic achievements. Au revoir! 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello world&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I managed to complete several academic tasks, which I would like to tell you more about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the discipline &amp;ldquo;Mathematical foundations of information security and information security&amp;rdquo;, I completed the second laboratory work, the topic of which was encryption using permutations. The topic of cryptography is very entertaining, and I could write a post about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She also completed the second laboratory work on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Scientific Programming&amp;rdquo;, which was aimed at gaining skills to work with the Markdown markup language. If you see this post, it means I&amp;rsquo;m doing well :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I completed two laboratory works on the discipline &amp;ldquo;Modeling of wireless networks&amp;rdquo;, thanks to which I remembered the basic methods of working with statistical data in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued studying French. A little more and this site will have the opportunity to choose French as the language (I&amp;rsquo;m kidding, I&amp;rsquo;m still a long way from that, but I can tell you what my name is).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will keep you informed of my academic achievements. Au revoir! 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control. Git.</title>
      <link>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/writing-technical-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZlataDyachenko.github.io/post/writing-technical-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control Systems (Version Control System, VCS)&lt;/strong&gt; used when several people are working on the same project. Usually, the main project tree is stored in a local or remote repository, to which access is configured for project participants. When making changes to the project content, the version control system allows you to fix them, combine changes made by different project participants, roll back to any earlier version of the project, if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;theoretical-information&#34;&gt;Theoretical information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In classical version control systems, a centralized model is used, assuming a single repository for storing files. Most version control functions are performed by a special server. The project participant (user) receives the version of files he needs before starting work through certain commands. After making changes, the user places the new version in the repository. At the same time, previous versions are not deleted from the central repository and you can return to them at any time. The server may not save the full version of the modified files, but perform a so—called delta compression - save only changes between successive versions, which reduces the amount of data stored.
Version control systems support the ability to track and resolve conflicts that may arise when several people work on a single file. You can merge (merge) changes made by different participants (automatically or manually), manually select the desired version, cancel the changes altogether or lock files for modification. Depending on the settings, the lock does not allow other users to get a working copy or prevents the OS file system from changing the working copy of the file, thus providing privileged access to only one user working with the file.
Version control systems can also provide additional, more flexible functionality. For example, they can support working with multiple versions of a single file, keeping a common history of changes up to the point of branching versions and their own change histories of each branch. In addition, information is usually available about which of the participants, when and what changes were made. Usually this kind of information is stored in the change log, access to which can be restricted. Unlike the classic ones, in distributed version control systems, a central repository is not mandatory.
Among the classic VCS, the most famous are CVS, Subversion, and among the distributed ones — Git, Bazaar, Mercurial. The principles of their work are similar, they differ mainly in the syntax of the commands used in the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is a distributed file version control system. The project was created by Linus Torvalds to manage the development of the Linux kernel. Currently supported by Junio Hamano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is designed as a set of programs specially designed for their use in scripts. This makes it convenient to create specialized version control systems based on Git or user interfaces. For example, Cogito is just such an example of a frontend to Git repositories, and StGit uses Git to manage a collection of patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git supports rapid separation and merging of versions, includes tools for visualization and navigation through the non-linear development history.
The Git version control system is a set of command-line programs. They can be accessed from the terminal by entering the git command with various options.
Due to the fact that Git is a distributed version control system, a backup copy of the local storage can be made by simple copying or archiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-concepts&#34;&gt;Basic concepts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repository&lt;/strong&gt; — the project in which the Git system was initialized. During initialization , a hidden folder is added to the project .git. The repository stores all working files and the history of their changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root folder of the project is &lt;strong&gt;workspace&lt;/strong&gt;. It contains all the files and folders necessary for its operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage&lt;/strong&gt; is the contents of a hidden folder.git. All workspace versions and service information are stored in this folder. The system automatically gives these versions a name consisting of letters and numbers. In the example above, these are be0f8e and d516600. It is not necessary to manipulate the folder .git manually. All work with the system is done by commands through special applications or the console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit&lt;/strong&gt; is a special command that saves a new version of the project and adds it to the repository. The saved file displays: all the changes that occurred in the workspace, the author of the changes and a short comment describing the essence of the changes. Each commit stores the complete state of the workspace, its folders and project files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-git-commands&#34;&gt;Basic git commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used git commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– creation of the main repository tree:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git init
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– getting updates (changes) of the current tree from the central repository:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git pull
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– sending all the changes made to the local tree to the central repository:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git push
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– view the list of modified files in the current directory:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git status
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– view current changes:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git diff
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– save current changes:
– add all modified and/or created files and/or directories:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git add .
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– add specific modified and/or created files and/or directories:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git add file_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– delete the file and/or directory from the repository index (while the file and/or directory remains in the local directory):&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git rm file_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– save added changes:
– save all added changes and all modified files:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git commit -am &amp;#39;Commit description&amp;#39;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– save the added changes with a comment through the built-in editor:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git commit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– creating a new branch based on the current one:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git checkout -b_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– switching to a certain branch:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git checkout branch name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– sending changes of a specific branch to the central repository:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git push origin_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– merging a branch with the current tree:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git merge --no-ff_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– deleting a branch:
– deleting a local branch already merged with the main tree:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git branch -d branch_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– forced deletion of a local branch:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git branch -D branch_name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;– deleting a branch from the central repository:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git push origin :branch name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;knowing-these-basics-you-can-already-start-working-with-projects&#34;&gt;Knowing these basics, you can already start working with projects.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
